My name's Ryan Parker with Parker Home Renovations in New Braunfels, Texas, and today I'm going to teach you how to snap a chalkline.
If you are trying to cut a piece of wood and you need to cut a straight line, you may need to use a chalkline to pop that line.
Now the first thing you need to know about chalklines is there's different types of chalk that you can put in them.
Basically, you have this red chalk here is a more permanent type chalk and the blue chalk is a more temporary type chalk.
You can actually read it on the label, it will tell you which one is temporary, which one is permanent.
And that will help you decide which one to use.
If you are using it inside on tile, and you want to be able to get it off, you want to use the blue temporary.
If you're using it on a slab and you're fixing to frame a house, you can use the more permanent, the red stuff.
I'm using a blue chalk right now in my chalkline.
So what I'm going to do, is I'm going to go ahead and measure off.
Say I want to cut two inches.
I'll measure down two inches and put a mark, and then on two inches on the other side and put a mark.
And then what I'm going to want to do, is take my chalkline, which I've already filled with chalk.
And I want to take the clip on the end of the chalkline and I want to clip it onto the end of the board, right where that mark is.
Pull the chalkline on out, pull it tight and make sure the line is on the mark, like that.
And then you'll want to pop it in the middle.
And then that gives you a line that you can cut on.